[{"id": "596dfa93cf3977a46e7ce447", "question": "The Statue of Liberty was a gift resulting from the diplomatic relationship between the United States and what country?", "answer": "France", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fb1bf51f497e33de805791a", "question": "What is the oldest active ballpark in Major League Baseball?", "answer": "Fenway Park", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bac8", "question": "How many tablespoons are in a cup?", "answer": "16", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5cefc125948005ec986edce4", "question": "Who is the eleventh member of the group LOONA to debut", "answer": "Go Won", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a88d", "question": "What country was policed by the Blackshirts for almost 25 years?", "answer": "Italy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fef96796ce05a3942286e9d", "question": "Which U.S. sitcom was the first to use a laugh track?", "answer": "\"The Hank McCune Show\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e72cf19d0874f1a5e2d1c29", "question": "How much liquid can be placed in a 10 gallon hat?", "answer": "3/4 of a gallon (US)", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe3e80338e4e5d4832e6309", "question": "Approximately, how much money did U.S. children spend on war bonds as part of the World War II effort?", "answer": "$1 billion", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5eb735115e259d7869087329", "question": "What was the nickname of the Battle of Khe Sanh?", "answer": "77-Day Siege", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a43e", "question": "Greenland is part of which kingdom?", "answer": "Kingdom of Denmark", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bb1", "question": "In 1926, the funeral of what silent movie star attracted a crowd of nearly 100,000 people to view the remains?", "answer": "Rudolph Valentino", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397eb", "question": "Which famous duo also recorded under the name \"Tom and Jerry\"?", "answer": "Simon and Garfunkel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4a5", "question": "Hg is the symbol for what element?", "answer": "Mercury", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe0e3affcbed638185eaa24", "question": "A building called \"The Gherkin\" graces which city's skyline?", "answer": "London", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c551", "question": "Which decade saw the first flight of a space shuttle commanded by a woman?", "answer": "1990s", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abd5", "question": "What is the capital of Cyprus?", "answer": "Nicosia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaeb", "question": "Which city is the capital of Tuscany?", "answer": "Florence", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ad", "question": "Who recorded the international hit single \"Poker Face\" in 2008?", "answer": "Lady Gaga", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339451", "question": "Who plays the role of Captain Jack Aubrey in the movie \"Master and Commander\"?", "answer": "Russell Crowe", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa79", "question": "Which is Earth's smallest ocean?", "answer": "Arctic Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b84", "question": "Who was the first singer to have five #1 singles off of one album?", "answer": "Michael Jackson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339933", "question": "What Martin Scorsese film was based on a 1986 book by Nicholas Pileggi about the Lucchese crime family?", "answer": "Goodfellas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b12e", "question": "The George M. Cohan song \"Over There\" was written as a rally cry during what war?", "answer": "World War I", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5cd40b2e685cf15b733e9888", "question": "What South American country's name comes from the Latin word for silver?", "answer": "Argentina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339804", "question": "What movie soundtrack is Eric Clapton's \"Tears in Heaven\" from?", "answer": "Rush", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339278", "question": "What country singer was the first person to \"turn a chair\" on season 2 of the TV show \"The Voice\"?", "answer": "Rae Lynn", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cc2", "question": "What is the last name of the \"Evil Dead\" series protagonist Ash?", "answer": "Williams", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c998", "question": "Caries refers to decay in what?", "answer": "Teeth", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b29d", "question": "What US president loved Fresca so much he had a soda tap installed for the Oval Office?", "answer": "Lyndon Johnson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe4e3cd06d333868d34d72f", "question": "Who invented the first steam locomotive?", "answer": "George Stephenson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a273", "question": "Who was the male star of the 1997 film \"Titanic\"?", "answer": "Leonardo DiCaprio", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "590720d03745b36be73039f3", "question": "What year did Disney release a 3D motion-capture adaptation of \"A Christmas Carol\"?", "answer": "2009", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cd6", "question": "What actress had the word \"Miss\" listed before her first name in the credits of \"The Waltons\"?", "answer": "Michael Learned", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adca", "question": "Which treaty organisation was set up as a counterpart to NATO?", "answer": "Warsaw Pact", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6013711e1381754895396389", "question": "Who was the original host of \"Wheel of Fortune\"?", "answer": "The original host was Chuck Woolery, a game show mainstay who left the show in 1981 over contract disputes.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b346", "question": "Which saint founded a monastery at Iona in the sixth century?", "answer": "Saint Columba", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bad6", "question": "In 1996, what became the first minivan to be named Motor Trend magazine's \"Car of the Year\"?", "answer": "Dodge Caravan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1c4", "question": "In the sitcom, \"Only Fools and Horses\" what is Rodney's middle name?", "answer": "Charlton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b35d", "question": "Who was the first American scientist to win a Nobel prize?", "answer": "Albert Michelson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a69", "question": "The line \"I never saw a purple cow\" is the beginning of a poem by what author?", "answer": "Gelett Burgess", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015e563fe83fe1f2a824bbc", "question": "The Islamic calendar is based on which cycle?", "answer": "Lunar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aa0", "question": "What 1996 comedy featured a hamster named Shelley?", "answer": "The Nutty Professor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f18", "question": "What author created Earthsea?", "answer": "Ursula K. Le Guin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a728c8f6bcd28c119383289", "question": "What is the first event in a Men's Heptathalon?", "answer": "60 Metres", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a52a", "question": "The Smithsonian Institution is located in which city?", "answer": "Washington D.C.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5cefc060948005ec986edcda", "question": "Who is the first member of the group LOONA to debut?", "answer": "Heejin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b27b", "question": "What African region has been ravaged by militia called the Janjaweed?", "answer": "Darfur", "category": "history"}, {"id": "594d070d1a1c922dd1ac64b4", "question": "Which town do Fred, Wilma, Barney, and Betty live in?", "answer": "Bedrock", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd81d1dd0de9af39e9d468b", "question": "What is the largest pyramid?", "answer": "Pyramid of Cholula", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b497649076251badbeaae", "question": "Where in the world was Richard Nixon when he delivered his infamous \"I am not a crook\" speech?", "answer": "Disney World (Orlando, Florida)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9c0", "question": "Which Nintendo character made the line \"Do a barrel roll!\" famous?", "answer": "Peppy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e61", "question": "Who provided the original voice for The Iron Giant?", "answer": "Vin Diesel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff66f6b52a821ff76ae8b1f", "question": "In Tennessee, it\u2019s illegal to hold office if you\u2019ve done what?", "answer": "Fought in a duel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133934d", "question": "What year did \"The Tonight Show\" first air?", "answer": "1954", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe77055eec85e375820b2f8", "question": "Which mountain range separates Europe from Asia?", "answer": "The Ural Mountains", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58b8d6aa2b42d4a3561a9f06", "question": "West Swan is a suburb in which Australian city?", "answer": "Perth", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff3c3094f032c0db195b489", "question": "Who was the first European to discover New Zealand?", "answer": "Abel Janszoon Tasman", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b933", "question": "What meal-in-a-box is called the San Francisco treat?", "answer": "Rice-a-Roni", "category": "general"}, {"id": "594d05dc1a1c922dd1ac64a5", "question": "What two countries have square flags?", "answer": "Switzerland and Vatican City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7f0", "question": "What kind of oil, a product of the flax plant, is used to make most oil paints?", "answer": "Linseed oil", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b2e", "question": "What former professional athlete was actress Halle Berry's first husband?", "answer": "David Justice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea3cc4ff048f679a45ab42", "question": "What Australian marsupial is often mistaken for a monkey?", "answer": "Cuscus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600f753da9e54d890926f707", "question": "How long is New Zealand\u2019s Ninety Mile Beach?", "answer": "55 miles", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59bb287ac9bff04efae6d750", "question": "Who wrote the book on which the Oscar winning film \"The Godfather\" was based?", "answer": "Mario Puzo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921d", "question": "In which movie does Hugh Grant play a London bookshop owner?", "answer": "Notting Hill", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4a952561d1b4d384d5d675", "question": "What are \"Castanets\"?", "answer": "A type of musical instrument", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ac9", "question": "In what year did the French author Charles Perrault die?", "answer": "1703", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133917f", "question": "Who is the Kindergarten Cop?", "answer": "Arnold Schwarzenneger", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397c3", "question": "What hit 1992 movie gave Geena Davis the chance to prove she could spit?", "answer": "A League of their Own", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e98", "question": "What novelist's most famous character is the aptly named Isadora Wing?", "answer": "Erica Jong's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6000edf09a72b906b34e3cf2", "question": "What is the name of the largest vein in the human body?", "answer": "The inferior vena cava", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133971f", "question": "Which Australian played James Bond?", "answer": "George Lazenby", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffcfdbb9dc5ec6cd98a8325", "question": "What novel is set on a desert planet inhabited by giant sandworms?", "answer": "Dune", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b98", "question": "Whose paintings include \"Campbell's Soup Can\" and \"Green Coca-Cola Bottles\"?", "answer": "Andy Warhol", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe904cd01dd7bf43be5e878", "question": "The Miami Marlins' baseball stadium is built on the former site of what other stadium?", "answer": "The Orange Bowl Stadium", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b656", "question": "\"Friends of Bill W.\" is another name for what?", "answer": "Alcoholics Anonymous", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393c0", "question": "What Al Pacino movie portrayed a bank robbery on August 22, 1972?", "answer": "Dog Day Afternoon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399b4", "question": "John Paul Jones was bassist and keyboardist for what rock band?", "answer": "Led Zeppelin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca4c", "question": "What would be scored by the Apgar score?", "answer": "Health of newborns", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133972f", "question": "What does Popeye have tattooed on his arm?", "answer": "An anchor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ca5", "question": "Who's the only character is \"Peter and the Wolf\" represented by a brass instrument?", "answer": "The wolf", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac59", "question": "What year did the red maple leaf design officially become Canada's flag?", "answer": "1965", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395d9", "question": "In The Simpsons, what does the old Radioactive Man #1 comic smell like according to Milhouse?", "answer": "His grandfather", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac9b", "question": "Who was prime minister of the United Kingdom from 1997 to 2007?", "answer": "Tony Blair", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5e72cce8d0874f1a5e2d1c25", "question": "What is a \"Winkle Picker\" or \"Winklepicker\"?", "answer": "An English long pointed shoe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339031", "question": "Jim Rhodes is the alter ego of which Marvel comic book hero?", "answer": "War Machine", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8bd", "question": "What is Barbie's last name?", "answer": "Roberts", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c97a", "question": "The North Star is also known as?", "answer": "Polaris", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59071d593745b36be73039d6", "question": "What operation brought over 1,500 German scientists, engineers and technicians following the end of World War II to the US to aid in military research?", "answer": "Operation Paperclip", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a12f", "question": "At what address did the TV's \"Addams Family\" live?", "answer": "0001 Cemetery Lane", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8f65101dd7bf43be5e831", "question": "What was the only NBA team Michael Jordan played for other than the Chicago Bulls?", "answer": "Washington Wizzards", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5ae", "question": "What is the largest joint in the body?", "answer": "The knee joint", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a711", "question": "The city of Santa Cruz is located on the shores of what bay?", "answer": "Monterey Bay", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e6", "question": "What name is given to the ancient Christian and Jewish underground burial chambers in and around Rome?", "answer": "Catacombs", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339825", "question": "What quintet featured Danny, Donnie, Joe, Jonathan and Jordan?", "answer": "New Kids on the Block", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef96b46ce05a3942286e9f", "question": "Who was the first sitting US President to throw the first pitch on Opening Day?", "answer": "William Howard Taft", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb5a", "question": "At a military funeral, the American flag is folded how many times?", "answer": "13", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9b9", "question": "What country is the \"pearl of the orient seas\"?", "answer": "Philippines", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392b4", "question": "Produced by Francis Ford Coppola, what Academy Award-winning film was released in 1974?", "answer": "The Godfather, Part II", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0b1e6e662d71a53650fd5", "question": "The Uffizi museum can be found in which city?", "answer": "Florence", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c90", "question": "What 1969 Kurt Vonnegut novel is subtitled \"The Children's Crusade\"?", "answer": "Slaughterhouse-Five", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9bc", "question": "What does \"Honolulu\" translate to in English?", "answer": "Sheltered harbor", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe6a36e20565ad31a57c7b4", "question": "What was the first U.S. company to be valued at $1 billion?", "answer": "U.S. Steel", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339048", "question": "Which Tennesee Williams play is about a Italian-American woman?", "answer": "The Rose Tattoo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc21", "question": "What year was the construction of the Eiffel Tower completed?", "answer": "1889", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f2e", "question": "Who wrote \"Il Milione\" while in prison?", "answer": "Marco Polo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be8f", "question": "Who was knocked out in 1974 by the \"rope-a-dope\" method?", "answer": "George Forman", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1f6", "question": "What year marked the end of production of the first generation Volkswagen Golf?", "answer": "1983", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a08", "question": "What snack shares its name with the famous cartoon strip by Charles M. Schulz?", "answer": "Peanuts", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338876", "question": "Who does Alice follow down the hole?", "answer": " The White Rabbit", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c831", "question": "The \"Wandering\" species of what bird has the longest wingspan in nature?", "answer": "Albatross", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a137", "question": "Which character from \"Beavis and Butthead\" has their own show?", "answer": "Daria", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7ce", "question": "In the Southern Hemisphere, summer begins in what month?", "answer": "December", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "591c35d2815febcc896f9260", "question": "Which part of the body is affected by Rhinitis?", "answer": "The nose", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1b4", "question": "Anthony Robert McMillan is more famous as who?", "answer": "Robbie Coltrane", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe73564eec85e375820b24a", "question": "Who said, \"A state of society where men may not speak their minds cannot long endure.\"?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffb5fb05dad637d903c8827", "question": "The Vatican owns a telescope in what U.S. state?", "answer": "Arizona", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7f9", "question": "What\u2019s the largest country entirely within the southern hemisphere?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9ab", "question": "What would you suffer from with Hypotension?", "answer": "Low blood pressure\u00a0", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a5c", "question": "According to his elementary school principal, what 1994 title character of an Oscar-winning movie had an IQ of 75?", "answer": "Forrest Gump", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "592eaf96f83302ff91e46494", "question": "What are juvenile goats called?", "answer": "Kids", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5febb0d97e83c707845b2109", "question": "What's the term for a leopard's spots?", "answer": "Rosettes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd6651da5bfecdd737e085b", "question": "How old did William Shakespeare live to be?", "answer": "52 years", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe733fdeec85e375820b22a", "question": "In which battle did Chinese general Zhang Hongfan destroy the last fleet of the Southern Song Dynasty?", "answer": "Battle of Yamen", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59e3f3965cb9e8bda6821364", "question": "When was the Rosetta Stone found?", "answer": "1799", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a109", "question": "Who does Fred Savage play on the TV show \"The Wonder Years\"?", "answer": "Kevin Arnold", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0a6", "question": "What is the literal translation of the word Brandy?", "answer": "Burned wine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ab1af9baab681b09292198", "question": "The Bugatti Veyron was designed and produced by which large automotive group?", "answer": "Volkswagen Group", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a500", "question": "What is the first nation you would reach after heading due east from New York City?", "answer": "Portugal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f00", "question": "What street gang rumbles with the Sharks in \"West Side Story\"?", "answer": "The Jets", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7fc", "question": "What is the generation of people born from 1946 to 1964 called?", "answer": "Baby Boomers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c543", "question": "What do goldfish lose if kept in dimly lit or running water?", "answer": "Their color", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339648", "question": "What was the nickname of Gene Hackman's character in The French Connection?", "answer": "Popeye", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ade9", "question": "The first Olympic Games were held in whose honor?", "answer": "Zeus'", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133942c", "question": "How many roles did Cheech Marin play in the 1996 movie \"From Dusk Till Dawn\"?", "answer": "Three", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff51c30ff04d658268c9315", "question": "In the 7th chapter of the Gospel of Luke, Jesus raises a young man from the dead in which village?", "answer": "Nain", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58d118f64fea7fe947a2228a", "question": "An adventurous penguin Tennessee Tuxedo had a sidekick named what?", "answer": "Chumley", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a626", "question": "Which is the westernmost state in the US?", "answer": "Alaska", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab57", "question": "Which former Soviet Republic in Central Asia has Tashkent as its capital?", "answer": "Uzbekistan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a7", "question": "Who played Mad Max Rockatansky?", "answer": "Mel Gibson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59067e5aff9c0647b50a8079", "question": "What two American astronauts passed away in February of 2016?", "answer": "Edgar Mitchell and Donald E. Williams", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bc7", "question": "Which food of the gods gives immortality?", "answer": "Ambrosia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffb5b835dad637d903c881b", "question": "What is the most-popular meat served on Christmas in the United Kingdom?", "answer": "Turkey meat", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601737ef44491cbd7c5a1790", "question": "During World War II, prisoners wearing a green triangle in a concentration camp signified the prisoners were what?", "answer": "Criminals or convicts (often working as kapos)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a46e", "question": "What is the Paris Gare Du Nord?", "answer": "A railway station", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b158", "question": "When did Princess Diana die in a car accident?", "answer": "August 31, 1997", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4fb", "question": "How many minutes does it take sunlight to reach Earth?", "answer": "8", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ffe4b7b47818f5674af01b1", "question": "From which novel is this quote \"I\u2019m the most terrific liar you ever saw in your life. It\u2019s awful.\"?", "answer": "\"The Catcher in the Rye\" (The main character, Holden Caulfield, fittingly says this early in the novel while describing himself.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c65e", "question": "When standing in sunlight, what vitamin does your body synthesize?", "answer": "D", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397d6", "question": "Who created the original Star Trek series?", "answer": "Gene Roddenberry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab13f1baab681b0929216f", "question": "What car manufacturer was the first to mass-produce and equip a production vehicle with a V4 engine?", "answer": "Lancia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b277", "question": "According to Betsy Ross' family, what was the first American flag made from?", "answer": "Hemp", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1fc", "question": "Who had an 1980's hit with the song \"Is There Something I Should Know\"?", "answer": "Duran Duran", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aac", "question": "What actress played Jane in the 2005 remake of the movie \"Fun with Dick and Jane\"?", "answer": "Tea Leoni", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ca3c5244f0f6af5b06662f", "question": "What London gentleman's club was the first to admit lady members in 1981?", "answer": "Reform Club", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397ab", "question": "What Guns N' Roses star decided his real name, William Bailey, wasn't cool enough?", "answer": "Axl Rose", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133887d", "question": "Who was King Lear's favorite daughter?", "answer": "Cordelia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea32edff048f679a45aaea", "question": "CH3COOH is the chemical formula for what common household item?", "answer": "Vinegar", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c412", "question": "What bird has the biggest eyes of any land animal?", "answer": "Ostrich", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600243b84be4723ccac2219a", "question": "Which semi-autobiographical novel by James Baldwin tells the story of John Grimes, a Harlem teenager in the 1930s?", "answer": "\"Go Tell It on the Mountain\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b54", "question": "Which cast member from the TV show \"Friends\" has a father who is a cast member on \"Days of Our Lives\"?", "answer": "Jennifer Aniston", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a432", "question": "In what country would you most likely encounter a Tasmanian devil?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600f755ea9e54d890926f70a", "question": "In Denmark, what is a Svangerskabsforebyggendemiddel?", "answer": "A condom", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4c7", "question": "What year did Suriname gain its independence from the Kingdom of the Netherlands?", "answer": "1975", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6012185063c99d48cd169af0", "question": "In Florida, only on Sundays, it is illegal for a single woman to do what?", "answer": "Skydive", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a3", "question": "What color is Shrek?", "answer": "Green", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133982b", "question": "What puppeteer created Kermit the Frog and Miss Piggy?", "answer": "Jim Henson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399ce", "question": "In what 2006 film does a family travel in a VW microbus to get to a beauty pageant?", "answer": "Little Miss Sunshine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa3913c73aa70ea0b70ad7", "question": "Which settlers added an \"r\" to Arkansas?", "answer": "French (They were told by natives from an Illinois tribe that people in the area now called Arkansas were called \"Akansa\".)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7d504877e98cb97778a63", "question": "Who won the Nobel Prize in Physics in 1918 for the services he rendered to the advancement of physics by his discovery of energy quanta?", "answer": "Max Planck", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7bd15877e98cb97778953", "question": "What is the only sea without any coasts?", "answer": "Sargasso", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe76e15eec85e375820b2d9", "question": "Which country did Barbados gain its independence from?", "answer": "United Kingdom", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015ec7ffe83fe1f2a824c03", "question": "Who in the New Testament got shipwrecked on one of his missionaries?", "answer": "Paul", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adcf", "question": "Who founded the \"American Red Cross\"?", "answer": "Clara Barton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b779", "question": "How many holes are there in a standard Ritz cracker?", "answer": "Seven", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339391", "question": "How many soldiers were set out to find Private Ryan?", "answer": "Eight", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58f168e3f7c52aae91cc07cb", "question": "What is the core in most pencils made from?", "answer": "Graphite", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396bd", "question": "U2's Paul Hewson is better known by which nickname?", "answer": "Bono", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a776", "question": "What was the nation of Thailand known as prior to 1949?", "answer": "Siam", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b5b", "question": "Which fairytale character slept for 20 years?", "answer": "Rip Van Winkle", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59ded166ea2747c8aff16d32", "question": "Mead is made primarily from what?", "answer": "Honey", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6003952057a0e35c43f83892", "question": "Any color plus black is called what?", "answer": "A shade", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2ff", "question": "Who did Pat Morita play on the ABC sitcom \"Happy Days\"?", "answer": "Arnold", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b9c", "question": "Carlo Collodi created which famous children's character?", "answer": "Pinocchio", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fe1", "question": "At what New York hotel was Sid Vicious accused of killing Nancy Spungen?", "answer": "The Chelsea Hotel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd81d04d0de9af39e9d468a", "question": "Why was 46 B.C.E. called the \"year of confusion\"?", "answer": "It had two extra months", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ab", "question": "Who does Emma Watson play in the Harry Potter films?", "answer": "Hermione", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b185", "question": "Who succeeded Ronald Reagan as the 41st President of the United States?", "answer": "George H.W. Bush", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd2c", "question": "In what sport are the Beaters in charge of batting away the Bludgers?", "answer": "Quidditch", "category": "general"}, {"id": "592201efa4edfd43a087addc", "question": "What year was the first \"Harry Potter\" novel published?", "answer": "1997", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e21", "question": "What movie is loosely based on Philip K. Dick's novel \"Do Androids Dream of Electric Sheep\"?", "answer": "Blade Runner", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bffc", "question": "What is another word for a bird watcher?", "answer": "Twitcher", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab95", "question": "What present-day country is Mount Ararat located in?", "answer": "Turkey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8c7", "question": "The point on land closest to the North Pole belongs to what nation?", "answer": "Denmark", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0bb", "question": "Which Rolling Stones hit was reputedly based on Martha Reeves and The Vandellas \"Dancing In The Street\"?", "answer": "I Can't Get No Satisfaction", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a644", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Buckeye State\"?", "answer": "Ohio", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd1e", "question": "What computer language uses as its logo a blue mug with red steam rising from it?", "answer": "Java", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5cb70bb8f96e155acab35d26", "question": "What is the longest running Star Trek series of all time in terms of total episodes?", "answer": "Star Trek: The Next Generation", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b800", "question": "What does a cartographer do?", "answer": "Makes maps", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5e2", "question": "What name is given to the fruit of an oak tree?", "answer": "An acorn", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8dc", "question": "At the delta of the Danube River, what body of water does it flow into?", "answer": "The Black Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b27c", "question": "Who used hypnotism to treat the hemophilia of Tsarevich Alexei?", "answer": "Rasputin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59ca3f0444f0f6af5b06664f", "question": "What is the capital of the US state New Hampshire?", "answer": "Concord", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe90a2201dd7bf43be5e896", "question": "The psychological test of human emotions and personality, using inkblots, is formally known as what?", "answer": "The Rorschach test", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395c2", "question": "In The Simpsons, what kind of factory is next door to where the Krusty the Clown show is taped?", "answer": "A box factory", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca2e", "question": "Paper and Mud Dauber are types of what?", "answer": "Wasp", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd8e", "question": "Who was sued in 1999 by Rosa Parks after they used her name to title a hit song?", "answer": "OutKast", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4b39f06d333868d34d6da", "question": "Who did Churchill call the \"American Carnot\" in World War II?", "answer": "General George Marshall", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd6638ea5bfecdd737e0851", "question": "Who was the youngest Chief Justice appointed to the U.S. Supreme Court?", "answer": "John Jay", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fec8b94ec223966ae8f8840", "question": "\"Mi Reflejo\" was a Spanish-speaking album released by which famous musician?", "answer": "Christina Aguilera", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fffa33173838c5c8a417f1f", "question": "Who created the first vaccine?", "answer": "Edward Jenner (He created a vaccine for smallpox.  He also coined the term \"vaccine\" from Variolae vaccinae, his term for cowpox.)", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff7bfb32b316f4693fb6794", "question": "The singer of which song also voiced Frosted Flakes\u2019 Tony the Tiger?", "answer": "Thurl Ravenscroft", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fedde0b6ce05a3942286daa", "question": "In what country was the first NFL regular-season game ever held outside of the United States?", "answer": "Mexico City hosted the Cardinals versus the 49ers in Oct 2005.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a532", "question": "The Guggenheim Museum is located in what city?", "answer": "New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6db", "question": "What name is given to a ball on a wire that is thrown in an Olympic event?", "answer": "Hammer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59a552c03e1c6f9840ba319d", "question": "Which Asian country has the calling code 82?", "answer": "South Korea", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a641", "question": "Lake Champlain is located in Vermont and in which other state?", "answer": "New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba4b", "question": "What were the Portsmouth Spartans renamed after the team was moved to Detroit?", "answer": "Detroit Lions", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d6f", "question": "What Nirvana and Smashing Pumpkins record produced later became the drummer in Garbage?", "answer": "Butch Vig", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe765f7eec85e375820b27a", "question": "Which famous figures are featured on Prague\u2019s astronomical clock?", "answer": "The 12 Apostles", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b6b", "question": "What future Oscar-winning actress played the title role on the 1960's sitcom \"Gidget\"?", "answer": "Sally Field", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b33f", "question": "Which fish, previously thought to be extinct was rediscovered In 1939?", "answer": "The Coelacanth", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a197", "question": "In the video game \"Darksiders\", which of the Four Horsemen of the Apocalypse do you play?", "answer": "War", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f7f", "question": "What was Bo Donaldson's backing band?", "answer": "The Heywoods", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c552", "question": "To be classified as perennial, a plant must have a life cycle of more than how many years?", "answer": "Two", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59cdb47c65ff7d326b622a89", "question": "What is Nelophobia the fear of?", "answer": "Glass", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e62", "question": "Who provided the original voice for Hank Hill?", "answer": "Mike Judge", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a78", "question": "In \"Ferris Bueller's Day Off\", what actor was listed in the credits simply as \"boy in police station\"?", "answer": "Charlie Sheen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f92", "question": "What actress earned an Oscar nomination for her first screen appearance in \"Alfie\"?", "answer": "Vivien Merchant", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8fe9a01dd7bf43be5e85c", "question": "What does \"Veni, vidi, vici\" translate into?", "answer": "I came, I saw, I conquered.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388eb", "question": "What is the dot in the \"i\" called?", "answer": "A tittle", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cbe", "question": "What fairytale girl eats the window pane of the witch's cottage?", "answer": "Gretel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fdc0d29469bb8041d07a059", "question": "Earl Grey tea is blended with oil extracted from what fruit?", "answer": "Bergamot Orange", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac5d", "question": "What shortage killed over one million Irish people in the 1840s?", "answer": "Potatoes", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac51", "question": "Who made the first popsicle?", "answer": "Frank Epperson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca11", "question": "What is the fear of lice called?", "answer": "Pediculophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fdc1039469bb8041d07a06c", "question": "Who coined the phrase \"junk food\"?", "answer": "Michael Jacobson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a561", "question": "What Ivy League University is located in New Haven, Connecticut?", "answer": "Yale University", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395dc", "question": "In The Simpsons, what was Martin's soap box racer named?", "answer": "The Honor Roller", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f76", "question": "What was Tom Petty's backing band?", "answer": "The Heartbreakers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acb2", "question": "What disease killed 20,000 Parisians in 1832?", "answer": "Cholera", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5909ce69bb53d1af658864f0", "question": "Who directed the 2003 film \"Elf\"?", "answer": "Jon Favreau", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a9", "question": "Who voices the character of scientist and inventor Professor John I.Q. Nerdelbaum Frink Jr. on \"The Simpsons\"?", "answer": "Hank Azaria", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcbf", "question": "What model was married to musician Tommy Lee?", "answer": "Pamela Anderson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b195", "question": "Which battle brought the end of Napoleon's European conquests?", "answer": "Battle of Waterloo", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be06", "question": "What sports term is also the name of the dimple at the bottom of a wine bottle?", "answer": "Punt", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b21", "question": "Stings first solo album was entitled \"The Dream of the Blue...\" what?", "answer": "Turtles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c5d", "question": "Who was the Roman God of Love?", "answer": "Cupid", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe76a09eec85e375820b2b8", "question": "True champagne can only come from grapes grown in the Champagne region of what country?", "answer": "France", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5c77ce4f24f0f7a362efd546", "question": "A-ha and Edward Grieg hail from what country ", "answer": "Norway", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fecc5e5ec223966ae8f8884", "question": "Infamous English prisoner, Charles Bronson, was played by what actor in the 2008 film \"Bronson\"?", "answer": "Tom Hardy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338da8", "question": "What breed of dog is Cujo?", "answer": "Saint Bernard", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e16", "question": "What cartoonist of \"Maus\" also created \"Topps Garbage Pail Kids\"?", "answer": "Art Spiegelman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c95f", "question": "What is the study of soil called?", "answer": "Pedology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b691", "question": "In the US, the horn of plenty is a common symbol of which holiday?", "answer": "Thanksgiving", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc38", "question": "What was the motto of the 1972 Munich Olympic games?", "answer": "The Happy Games", "category": "general"}]